[{"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924d", "question": "What newspaper does Clark Kent work for?", "answer": "The Daily Planet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab4fa0b8cce1e6fda7049", "question": "What English word has the most definitions/meanings?", "answer": "Run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c63", "question": "What was Gatsby's first name in the book \"The Great Gatsby\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Jay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff1401eb0ee8c595b6d3995", "question": "Which painting was stolen from the Louvre in 1911 and not returned for over two years?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f08c01dd7bf43be5e7fe", "question": "What is the key difference between pizza and flatbread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6003958357a0e35c43f83894", "question": "What is the term for reproducing a texture by laying paper over it and rubbing it with a pencil or crayon?", "answer": "Frottage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5e", "question": "What cut of beef, often used for hamburger, is also called the \"seven-bone steak\"?", "answer": "Chuck steak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e032fe83fe1f2a824b88", "question": "Who ran for President of the United States with the campaign slogan \"A chicken in every pot and a car in every garage\"?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffd", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a7", "question": "What leaf appears on the Canadian flag?", "answer": "The Maple Leaf", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf37", "question": "Papaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The pope", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b57181f67df192a942e335b", "question": "What kind of creature was Sam on \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1a7bbaab681b09292194", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66d65a5bfecdd737e08a0", "question": "What did the world's first text message say?", "answer": "Merry Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa86", "question": "What is the capital of Oman?", "answer": "Muscat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca90", "question": "Wallace Carothers is known as the inventor of what?", "answer": "Nylon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f71d5a9e54d890926f6e6", "question": "What Texas National Park is larger than the state of Rhode Island?", "answer": "Big Bend National Park -- Established in 1935, it is located along the Rio Grande River in southern Texas\u2019s Chihuahuan Desert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b385", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ad1501dd7bf43be5e775", "question": "Why are school buses yellow?", "answer": "Easier to spot in your peripheral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7357feec85e375820b24c", "question": "Who said, \"Personally I\u2019m always ready to learn, although I do not always like being taught.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb3", "question": "Which US gangster described himself as a used furniture dealer on his business card?", "answer": "Al Capone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb00", "question": "Azote is an old name for what element?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea47b6ff048f679a45abac", "question": "What was the element mercury named after?", "answer": "The Roman messenger god", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd6af7e83c707845b216c", "question": "Where was the maiden edition of the tennis World Team Cup held?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3cf4b4f032c0db195b490", "question": "What was a temple on the Athenian Acropolis dedicated to the goddess Athena?", "answer": "The Parthenon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339964", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", before becoming a tavern owner, what was Moe's profession?", "answer": "Boxer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8d66ce05a3942286d75", "question": "Where is the headquarters of Nintendo?", "answer": "Kyoto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590089dccf842fa4c4ba968c", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f2", "question": "In the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\", how many of the Ryan brothers were soldiers?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65f031f3c0ead6880d633", "question": "Which kind of bulbs were once exchanged as a form of currency?", "answer": "Tulips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f12bff048f679a45aaaf", "question": "What are baby owls called?", "answer": "Owlets or nestlings", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f3f901dd7bf43be5e81c", "question": "UNICEF stands for what?", "answer": "The United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b62ce662d71a53651003", "question": "\"Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8a94301dd7bf43be5e74b", "question": "What is the legal term for a voluntary written statement made under oath?", "answer": "Affidavit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe699a420565ad31a57c749", "question": "What was the first probe to land on Venus?", "answer": "Venera 9", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea35fdff048f679a45ab07", "question": "On what part of your body would you find the \"pinna\"?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a448", "question": "Which country is home to the spring festival called \"Holi\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe000ae1cf6db9ac4808d15", "question": "Which country has the oldest airport in the world that's still in operation?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad4", "question": "In 2004, what golfer ended Tiger Woods' reign as the number 1 men's player in the world?", "answer": "Vijay Singh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937c", "question": "What actor plays the role of the Bible salesman in the movie \"O Brother, Where Art Thou\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaeb", "question": "Which city is the capital of Tuscany?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ffcafe83fe1f2a824c50", "question": "In the film \"Saving Private Ryan,\" who played the role of private Ryan?", "answer": "Ironically Matt Damon was given this role by Spielberg partly due to his lack of fame.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a0", "question": "According to the Gospels, what did the Wise Men bring?", "answer": "Gold, Frankincense, and Myrrh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d07261a1c922dd1ac64b5", "question": "Who says, \"Th-th-th-that's all folks!\"?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f837cee580c7f8fd1e60", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Mount Whitney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f013745b36be73039e7", "question": "What short name does Dana use to refer to her son in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Coop", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc8560fabc30a8194e188af", "question": "In which three films did Bill Paxton and Michael Bien both have roles?", "answer": "\"Terminator\", \"Aliens\" and \"Tombstone\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ca", "question": "What decade was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" set in?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b30d01dd7bf43be5e7a7", "question": "What US state is home to the Crazy Horse Memorial?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66c5852a821ff76ae8b11", "question": "During which year was cocaine removed as an ingredient in Coca Cola?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56b", "question": "What is Lipton the world's biggest-selling brand of?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fccea4edfd43a087adc1", "question": "What number is represented by \"L\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "50", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d7", "question": "In Norse mythology, what was the name of the monster killed by Beowulf?", "answer": "Grendel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596761c52b59efe0e9417ea5", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ea", "question": "In which country was the Michelin tire company founded in 1889?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f5658333a95c66dc4fe758", "question": "Which number system uses only the symbols 1 and 0?", "answer": "The binary system", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ff", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role as a drill sergeant in the movie \"An Officer and a  Gentleman\"?", "answer": "Louis Gossett Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90ff6dd7247dfc0fa0030a", "question": "Under what name was \"Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\" published in the US?", "answer": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf4", "question": "Who wrote the novel, \"Dragon's Teeth\"?", "answer": "Upton Sinclair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a022", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who is Stewie's half-brother and nemesis?", "answer": "Bertram", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339483", "question": "What powers Monstropolis in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Screams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cae", "question": "Who wrote \"Tarzan of the Apes\" in 1912?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5967610c2b59efe0e9417ea1", "question": "The fear of some unknown evil is called what?", "answer": "Panphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ea1808d98002fdd6339f", "question": "Stephen King's \"The Shining\" is set at which hotel?", "answer": "Overlook Hotel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cb2dbb53d1af658864d6", "question": "Who wrote the 1994 novel \"Inspector Proby\u2019s Christmas\"?", "answer": "John Gano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a044", "question": "What alien did Ben 10 first turn into in \"Ben 10: Alien Force\"?", "answer": "Swampfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43e", "question": "Who was the longest reigning Prime Minister of Britain in the 20th Century?", "answer": "Margaret Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad7", "question": "What novel begins with the words \"Marley was dead...\"?", "answer": "A Christmas Carol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a6ef6c0f9723ab15cb58", "question": "What is the only birthstone that is not a mineral?", "answer": "Pearl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab7a00b8cce1e6fda704f", "question": "Which Jamaican runner is an 11-time world champion and holds the record in the 100 and 200-meter race?", "answer": "Usain Bolt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa38", "question": "What is the capital of the Democratic Republic of Congo?", "answer": "Kinshasa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a457", "question": "How many territories are there in Canada?", "answer": "3", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c517", "question": "What is a cross between a blackberry and a raspberry?", "answer": "Boysenberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391be", "question": "In which film did Paul Newman play a crime boss named John Rooney?", "answer": "Road to Perdition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fd", "question": "Who is Patricia Mae Andrzejewski better known as?", "answer": "Pat Benatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff516b0ff04d658268c92f3", "question": "Which pizza chain was the first to deliver a pie to space?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c2", "question": "What do the letters MG stand for in the British sports car?", "answer": "Morris Garage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ec7260957c9fcac0ce71981", "question": "Who played Jason Mendoza in the popular TV series, \"The Good Place\"?", "answer": "Manny Jacinto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7f", "question": "Who played Kate Austen on the ABC series \"Lost\"?", "answer": "Evangeline Lilly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a4", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for the inventor of the cyclotron?", "answer": "Lawrencium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac01", "question": "The Plains of Abraham is in which Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b268", "question": "What metal was found in Nevada's famed Comstock Lode?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47d", "question": "What year saw the Battle of the Plains of Abraham?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb8", "question": "What Thornton Wilder play is set in the town of Grovers Corners, New Hampshire?", "answer": "Our Town", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfab", "question": "What are Tracy Thorn and Ben Watt collectively known as?", "answer": "Everything But The Girl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbc", "question": "If you suffer from ailurophobia what are you afraid of?", "answer": "Cats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa8ce6ce05a3942286ed7", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1991 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acee", "question": "Which Argentinean Marxist, who became a bedroom poster icon of the 1960s, was once one of Fidel Castro's commander?", "answer": "Ernesto (Che) Guevara", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70b", "question": "Who brings gifts to the children of Brazil and Peru?", "answer": "Papa Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a5be20565ad31a57c7d0", "question": "Who was France's first president and last emperor?", "answer": "Napoleon III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c551", "question": "Which decade saw the first flight of a space shuttle commanded by a woman?", "answer": "1990s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf7", "question": "What company owns both the Hot Wheels and Matchbox brands?", "answer": "Mattel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ee", "question": "Which year was Queen Elizabeth II coronated in?", "answer": "1953", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a0", "question": "Which actress played alongside Arnold Schwarzenegger in the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Sharon Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338999", "question": "The story of Samson appears in which book of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Judges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9f", "question": "In what two California cities did Neil Young say he looked for a \"Heart of Gold\"?", "answer": "Hollywood and Redwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af34", "question": "Which treaty ended the war between Germany and the Allied Powers in World War I?", "answer": "Treaty of Versailles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975d", "question": "Cameron Crowe directed which Tom Cruise, Renee Zellwegger movie?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d0", "question": "How many guns does Travis buy in the movie \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdc02e347d002c297e4e4", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecb", "question": "In 1553, Lady Jane Grey was Queen of England for how many days?", "answer": "9", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad30", "question": "What US president endorsed the Louisiana Purchase in 1803?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76f3eeec85e375820b2e5", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3e", "question": "The Oscar for humanitarian work is named for what actor?", "answer": "Jean Hersholt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d3", "question": "In which country was the singer Mika born?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc29dec223966ae8f8877", "question": "Which member of boxing\u2019s \"Fabulous Four\" was the only one who defeated each of the other three at least once?", "answer": "Sugar Ray Leonard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d4702ff8e329de4f87788f", "question": "In electronics, what does the word modem stand for?", "answer": "Modulator-demodulator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910d", "question": "What is the name of Viktor Frankl's best-selling 1946 book?", "answer": "Man's Search for Meaning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd6", "question": "Who wrote the poem \"Anthem for Doomed Youth\"?", "answer": "Wilfred Owen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a741", "question": "What river flows along the northern border of Kentucky?", "answer": "Ohio River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986c", "question": "In Disney's \"Cinderella\", what article of clothing does she accidentally leave behind at the ball?", "answer": "A glass slipper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f0", "question": "What was the name of the character portrayed by Angela Lansbury in \"Murder, She Wrote\"?", "answer": "Jessica Fletcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb0", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"Autumn Sonata\"?", "answer": "Ingrid Bergman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c44", "question": "What popular statue was designed by Fredric-Auguste Bartholdi?", "answer": "Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990af96b72eedf883a8c708", "question": "Who recorded the song \"I Can't Explain\" in 1964?", "answer": "The Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3e", "question": "What year was Anthony Hopkins knighted by Queen Elizabeth II?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6d", "question": "Who painted \"Irises\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a81c20565ad31a57c7f3", "question": "What children's author also invented a surgical device?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda4", "question": "What group's honor society is the Order of the Arrow?", "answer": "The Boy Scouts of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2e", "question": "What U.S. states were once independent republics?", "answer": "Texas and Hawaii", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a712", "question": "Which US state is home to Lake Havasu City?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66b", "question": "Which US state is home to White Sands National Monument?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029f48cad1ec93f27df75e", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b8", "question": "What is Dr. Zhivago's first name?", "answer": "Yuri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d474caf8e329de4f8778a0", "question": "The Balfour Declaration was published in what year?", "answer": "1917", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cd", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Reverend Lovejoy's first name?", "answer": "Timothy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c902", "question": "What is the fear of nudity known as?", "answer": "Gymnophobia or Nudophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2bb", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was married four times herself?", "answer": "Catherine Parr", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd55cec223966ae8f88d0", "question": "\"You\u2019re gonna need a bigger boat\" originated in what movie?", "answer": "\"Jaws\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0d", "question": "The time-traveling scientist in the TV show \"Quantum Leap\" shares his name with what playwright?", "answer": "Samuel Beckett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbebf6ce05a3942286ef6", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Ol' Blue Eyes\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339462", "question": "Who is Sulley's sidekick in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b141", "question": "Who did Bill Clinton defeat in the 1996 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Bob Dole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c496", "question": "How many throwing events are there in a decathlon?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339214", "question": "What is the name of the soap opera that Miranda loves watching in \"Sex and the City\"?", "answer": "Jules and Mimi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956a", "question": "What was nominated for an outstanding children's program Emmy in 1992?", "answer": "Winne the Pooh and Christmas Too", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973a", "question": "Who composed the jazz classic \"I Got Rhythm\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec63fe83fe1f2a824c00", "question": "In what year was Valentine's Day removed from the Roman calendar?", "answer": "1969", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd8", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"hula\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d3", "question": "What famous American was nicknamed \"The Lone Eagle\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fb", "question": "Who was the first Jewish Miss America?", "answer": "Bess Myerson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c6", "question": "The Great Gazoo was an alien in which cartoon series?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601371ad138175489539638c", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him huge royalties: at the peak of the show's popularity, he took home $800,000 to $900,000 annually.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af10", "question": "What was the first American city to host the Summer Olympics?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0db34fcbed638185eaa08", "question": "Where is the only tropical botanical garden listed on UNESCO's World Heritage Site list?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa3", "question": "The piri piri pepper is commonly called what?", "answer": "African bird's eye chili", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b31", "question": "What two colors are the cat's hat in \"The Cat in the Hat\"?", "answer": "Red and white", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c6", "question": "Singer Stefani Joanne Angelina Germanotta is better known by what stage name?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7298a9e54d890926f6ec", "question": "In which U.S. city can you stroll down 6 1/2 Avenue?", "answer": "New York City -- Made official in 2012, the street is situated between 6th Avenue and 7th Avenue.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a739", "question": "Klamath Lake is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c934", "question": "The Campbell-Stokes Recorder measures what with a glass ball?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17a", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Next\"?", "answer": "The Sensational Alex Harvey Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb28", "question": "In baseball score-keeping, what number represents the third baseman's position?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad07", "question": "What year, approximately, was the first beer brewed?", "answer": "6,000 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c54e877e98cb977789ad", "question": "\"Blucifer\" is the nickname for which city's iconic horse statue?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b511", "question": "How many days were there in 2004?", "answer": "366", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc15c4469bb8041d07a08c", "question": "What does \"dim sum\" mean in English?", "answer": "Touching heart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e7", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a seashell?", "answer": "Conchiglie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9aff08b8581f80b092c1", "question": "What cartoon character did artist Matt Furie decide to kill in 2017, after it became associated with white nationalism against his will?", "answer": "Pepe the Frog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad16", "question": "Henry VIII was a member of what dynastic house of the English monarchy?", "answer": "Tudor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55e", "question": "What is the name for the longest side of a right-angled triangle?", "answer": "Hypotenuse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4d", "question": "The Clio Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Advertising", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4edf406d333868d34d771", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f2", "question": "Who is the lead guitarist in the band \"The Who\"?", "answer": "Pete Townsend", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf70", "question": "What is a popular 1990's slang for very short cutoff jeans?", "answer": "Daisy dukes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a787", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ef", "question": "Which US state is home to Joshua Tree National Park?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1e", "question": "Which royal palace was damaged by fire in 1986?", "answer": "Hampton Court Palace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339123", "question": "Which artist created the appearance of Babar the Elephant?", "answer": "Jean de Brunhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09f", "question": "How many wine gallons does a \"half pipe\" barrel contain?", "answer": "63", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4d", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Steel\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c874fbde8045e48466d9", "question": "What is a word for a flock of ravens?", "answer": "Conspiracy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27f", "question": "What word did Alexander Graham Bell suggest for answering the phone?", "answer": "Ahoy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894a", "question": "Ray Bradbury's novel \"Fahrenheit 451\" was serialized in the March, April and May issues of what popular magazine?", "answer": "Playboy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c967", "question": "What is the fear of flying called?", "answer": "Aviatophobia or pteromerhanophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45f", "question": "What is the active ingredient in smelling salts?", "answer": "Ammonia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff667ec52a821ff76ae8b00", "question": "The myth that carrots improve your vision is rooted in a propaganda campaign from which war?", "answer": "World War II (To keep the use of radar a secret. British officials launched a campaign stating eating carrots improved night vision.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cb41877e98cb97778a17", "question": "The ancient Phoenician city of Constantine is located in what modern-day Arab country?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c73b877e98cb977789c9", "question": "Which national capital does the Vltava River flow through?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31d", "question": "John Travolta, Samuel Jackson, Uma Thurman starred in which 1994 Quentin Tarantino film?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cbffa6de0eb824d4052d6", "question": "Where is the world's largest greenhouse?", "answer": "Cornwall, England -- The Eden Project is home to more than one million plants. It features two hexagonally-patterned biomes.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61a", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65608ae7e414034b5aebe", "question": "What creature guarded the gates to the underworld?", "answer": "A three-headed dog named Cerberus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c7", "question": "US President James Garfield died of what cause?", "answer": "He was shot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe655b3ae7e414034b5aeb8", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d45", "question": "What folk hero is said to have been born in Loxley, South Yorkshire?", "answer": "Robin Hood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907a", "question": "Who was the Roman god of agriculture?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacb", "question": "Topeka is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a221", "question": "Who played Beau Geste in the 1939 film by the same name?", "answer": "Gary Cooper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fda", "question": "Pax was the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d5", "question": "Which South American country takes its name from Christopher Columbus?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59220369a4edfd43a087ade2", "question": "Marzipan is made of which ground nut?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51247ff04d658268c92ce", "question": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of what Egyptian goddess?", "answer": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of the Egyptian goddess\u00a0Isis.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb63c7e83c707845b2125", "question": "What is a hybrid of a cow and bison called?", "answer": "Beefalo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f7", "question": "What is better than stone in the paper, stone, scissors game?", "answer": "Paper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398aa", "question": "What disability does Dustin Hoffman's character have in the movie \"Rain Man\"?", "answer": "Autism", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88a", "question": "What historic plaza is named for the first publisher of the \"Dallas Morning News\"?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078b7a0eee65b76b9f2669", "question": "Which dung beetle was worshipped by the ancient Egyptians?", "answer": "Scarab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b8", "question": "Which novel is the movie \"Blade Runner\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524730736d4be723796b71", "question": "What is the longest town name in Europe?", "answer": "Llanfair\u00adpwllgwyngyll\u00adgogery\u00adchwyrn\u00addrobwll\u00adllan\u00adtysilio\u00adgogo\u00adgoch, or simply Llanfairpwllgwyngyll", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1f", "question": "What everyday item did John Walker invent?", "answer": "Friction matches", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ab", "question": "\"Mayberry RFD\" was a spin-off from what other TV series?", "answer": "The Andy Griffith Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90cf8052800b05cac20f0a", "question": "What is Sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b679", "question": "Leather is the traditional gift for which wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Third", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cf", "question": "The berries of the juniper tree are used to flavour which alcoholic drink?\u00a0", "answer": "Gin\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2c", "question": "What painting was stolen in broad daylight from a museum in Oslo in 2004?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b724", "question": "Danish postmaster Einar Holboll is credited with the 1903 creation of what?", "answer": "Christmas Seals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c0", "question": "Lake Vanern is the largest lake in which country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7bf34877e98cb97778966", "question": "Lake Titicaca sits on the border between what two nations?", "answer": "Bolivia and Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5922022fa4edfd43a087addd", "question": "What is the first day of Lent called?", "answer": "Ash Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b16e", "question": "What decade saw the completion of the Empire State Building?", "answer": "1930's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65d", "question": "How many feet does a snail have?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b88521d8c1817608d53f1", "question": "Roquefort, Feta and Manchego are all cheeses made from the milk of which animal?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85e", "question": "What does a hygrometer measure?", "answer": "Humidity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad20", "question": "Which confectioner invented the heart-shaped Valentine's Day candy box?", "answer": "Richard Cadbury", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f4c6ff048f679a45aacb", "question": "Lockiophobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Childbirth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edd", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a2f520565ad31a57c7af", "question": "Who is Uncle Sam's female equivalent?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5611c73aa70ea0b70b27", "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b361e662d71a53650fde", "question": "Which novel starts with Colonel Aureliano facing a firing squad?", "answer": "\"One Hundred Years of Solitude\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9a", "question": "What actress replaced Shannen Doherty on the TV show \"Charmed\"?", "answer": "Rose McGowan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ad", "question": "What was the Asian nation of Myanmar known as prior to 1989?", "answer": "Burma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cf", "question": "The offspring of a male lion and a female tiger is known by what name?", "answer": "Liger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5df", "question": "Which state is located directly west of Louisiana?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a518", "question": "Sofia is the capital of which nation?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea77bfff048f679a45abce", "question": "Meningitis is characterized by what major symptoms?", "answer": "Stiff neck, sudden high fever and a severe headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac4", "question": "What is the name for the number 1 followed by 100 zeros?", "answer": "Googol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4226ce05a3942286dd8", "question": "What was the name of the 1976 Led Zeppelin concert film?", "answer": "The Song Remains the Same", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339198", "question": "What instrument does Meg White play in the band White Stripes?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca20", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2cf3e2596a59cbdfbd36d", "question": "Who said, \"There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3cffa4f032c0db195b495", "question": "What was the name of the military nobility of medieval and early-modern Japan?", "answer": "Samurai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978e", "question": "What is the name of the coolest girl gang in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Pink Ladies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5651833a95c66dc4fe754", "question": "What was Nancy Davis Reagan's birth name?", "answer": "Anne Frances Robbins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c5", "question": "What are the three main sections of an insect's body?", "answer": "The head, the abdomen and the thorax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4136ff048f679a45ab6e", "question": "What connects flower buds to the stem?", "answer": "Sepals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339338", "question": "What US state is Sheldon from the TV show \"The Big Bang Theory\" from?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67c", "question": "Which of the Hawaiian Islands is nicknamed the \"Valley Isle\"?", "answer": "Maui", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950f", "question": "Who voiced the character Atta in the movie \"A Bug's Life\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis Dreyfuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bc", "question": "What is the name of Kathy Bates' character in the movie \"Misery\"?", "answer": "Annie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaa5e7e83c707845b20de", "question": "A scientist at which company invented the pH scale?", "answer": "Carlsberg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's bowling ball?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14036b0ee8c595b6d3997", "question": "The Last Supper mural originally included which body part of Christ that has since been removed?", "answer": "Feet", "category": "arts"}]